#Encodergasm Presents
～
Here, nobody, here.
（んぴゅー）ここ 誰も いない
Always, alone.
ずっと １人
38th district is sunny.
（天気予報）第38地区 晴れ
一時 小石
Slight rock showers.
Chance of rock showers today is 20%.
本日の降石確率は20％
第39地区 曇り
39th district is cloudy.
Chance of rock showers this afternoon is 10%.
午後の降石確率は10％
Bebop, here, here!  Welcome!
（エド）ビバップ 来た 来た
いらっしゃーい！
んにゃああああああああ
Chance of rock showers today is 90%...
（天気予報）本日の降石確率90％
あり？
Now, it's time for today's news topics.
（アナウンサー１）さて 本日の
ニューストピックの時間です
Today, we'll discuss the mysterious land paintings...
今日は旧南米地区に
突如 出現した―
...that suddenly appeared in what was South America.
謎の地上絵について
考えてみたいと思います
解説は いつものように
超常現象研究家の…
As usual, we have commentaries by a researcher of supernatural phenomena...
（ユーリ）はい
ユーリ･ケラーマンです
Me, Yuuri Kellerman.
ユーリさん
今回の地上絵なんですけどねえ
Yuuri, about these land paintings...
ははあ ええ 僕が考えるに
あれは やっぱり―
Yes, yes.  Well, I believe that it was some sort of a message.
メッセージではないかと
思うわけなんですよ
（アナウンサー１）
ええと それは誰からの？
まさか…
Um, who would it be from...?  Can it be...?
（ユーリ）宇宙人ですよ
決まってるじゃないですか
Aliens!  It has to be from aliens!
（アナウンサー１）
えっ あっ しかし
However, the land paintings were drawn by lasers coming from satellites...
今回の地上絵は人工衛星からの
ビームによって描かれたもので―
警察は衛星にハッキングした―
The police think it was a prank pulled by a hacker who got into the satellite.
ハッカーのいたずらという
見解ですし…
現に犯人に対して―
They already have a bounty of 8 million woolongs on the culprit...
800万ウーロンの
賞金を懸けているわけですが
（ユーリ）いいですか？
800万の賞金などは政府の陰謀
Listen carefully.  The bounty of 8 million is a conspiracy of the government.
たとえレーザーによって
描かれたものだったとしてもですよ
Even if it WAS drawn by a laser, there IS the possibility...
そのハッカーの頭の中に―
...that aliens put a message into the brain of that hacker.
宇宙人からのメッセージが
届いたという可能性もあります
またしても政府は隠している
Once again, the government is hiding something from us.
はあ 秘密結社ですか？
I see...  A secret cult...
（ユーリ）そうです！
Yes!  And THAT is the mystery that I have been searching for all this time!
それこそ私が
長年 追い求めていた謎です
I'll pass on this one after all.
（スパイク）やっぱ俺
やめとくわ 今回
（ジェット）あいつと２人かよ
You're leaving me alone with her?
Nothing wrong with it.  She's gung-ho about it.
いいじゃねえか
向こうは やる気満々だ
女にリードされるのは性に合わん
I'm not the type to be led around by women.
リードすりゃあいいだろ
Then lead HER around.
I'm even less the type to do that.
そりゃ もっと性に合わん
It's easier to...
（フェイ）
800万は ３で割るより―
...divide 8 million between two than three.
２で割るほうが
気持ちよく分けられるわ
これだ
Here we go.
I'm appalled.  You're afraid of hackers?
あきれるわね
ハッカーが怖いだなんて
嫌いなんだよ
そういう面倒くさいのは
I just hate tedious work like that.
（フェイ）ハッキングなんて
せこいことやってるやつは―
Guys cheap enough to hack into things are depressed pale fatsos with glasses.
暗くてメガネで色白のデブ
And I'm sure he's a demented otaku with smelly feet.
おまけに足が臭い
性格ゆがんだオタクでしょ？
Piece of cake!
楽勝じゃない
お前 なんか恨みでもあるのか？
Do you have something against someone like that?
そりゃ お前が若い頃は
そうだったかもしれんがな
I mean, they might've all been like that when you were young...
あら 私があんたより
老けてるとでも言うわけ？
You're saying I look older than you?
女は見た目じゃ分からんからな
You can't tell a woman's age just by looking at her.
（フェイ）そう 見た目じゃ
分かんないわよね
Exactly.
You can't tell just by looking that I can do things like this...
私がこんなことも
できちゃうなんて
そこしか知らん
That's ALL I know of you.
（スパイク）いいコンビだぜ
You guys make a good team.
（フェイ）早くしなさいよ
Hurry up!
地球土産 待ってるぜ
I'll be waiting for a souvenir from Earth.
地球産に ろくなもんはねえよ
There's nothing made on Earth that's good.
（アナウンサー２）
さて 今回の この事件ですが
Well...
About this incident... apparently, a pretty...
かなり昔の人工衛星を
ハッキングしたものと思われ―
...old artificial satellite has been hacked into.
The investigation is taking longer than expected because...
その衛星へのアクセスコードが
既に失われているため―
...the access code to that satellite has been long lost.
捜査が
難航しているようなんですが…
さて 解説のアムジャッドさん
Now, a commentary from Mr.  Amjad.
（アムジャッド）はいはい
Yes, yes.
地球とハッカーの
関係についてなんですが…
About the relationship between Earth and the hacker...
そうですね
50年前のゲート事件以来―
Yes.  Since the Gate accident 50 years ago...
...the people of Earth have migrated underground as a result...
月のかけらの落下による
気象変化のために―
全ての生活空間を―
...of the change in climate, namely moon rocks falling onto the planet.
地下へと移している
地球人たちにとって―
コンピューターによって作られた
宇宙ネットは―
To them, the 'space network' created by computers is...
宇宙に住む人々とつながるために
必要不可欠な場所なんです
...necessary for them to stay in contact with those living in space.
なるほど
I see.
それが優秀なハッカーを育てる
基盤になっているわけですね
That's becoming a foundation to create outstanding hackers.
（エド）
ういいいいいいいいいいいいいん
どーん　があああああああ
ばばばばばばばばばばばばばばば
ぶううううううううううううううん
きいいいいいいいいいいいいいいん
（エド）んやああああ
（警官１）ラディカルエドワード
警察だ！ 出てこい
Radical Edward!
It's the police!  Come out!
（エド）はーい！
（警官１）うわっ
Yeah!
（エド）エヘヘ
（警官２）何だ？ どうした
What?  What's wrong?
（警官１）出た…
I saw it!
（警官２）うわっ！ 何で？
（警官１）誰も乗ってないのに！
Why!?
There's nobody in there!
きいいいいいいいいいいいいん
ぐおおおおおおおおおおおおおおん
ばばばばばばばーん
Mistake, mistake.
失敗 失敗　えへへへへ
Okay.
（フェイ）いい？
This is where the satellite was when it was hacked.
ハッキングされた衛星の
当時の位置は ここ
This is where it could be accessed from.
それにアクセス可能な地域は これ
I'll look at all the antennae that can transmit light signals one by one.
私は この範囲の
光通信可能なアンテナを―
しらみつぶしに あたるわ
こっちは めぼしいハッカーを
聞き込みに回ってみる
I'll ask around for info on any prominent hackers in the area.
ビバップ 地上絵の賞金首を
捜してるのか
Bebop's lookin' for land picture criminal...
All right!
よーし！
エヘヘ
昔々の衛星ちゃん
アクセスコードは どこでしょう？
Satellite of long, long ago...
Where in the world is your access code?
さて とりあえず
今 通信中のアンテナはと
Okay.  Let's start with all the antennae that are currently communicating...
あっ… くう
そら きっとエドだ　おっさん
That's probably Ed, man.
身長２メートルの大男らしいぜ
I hear he's a huge guy, 2 meters tall.
なんでも
元バスケの選手だったんだって
Supposedly, he used to be a basketball player.
知ってる 知ってる エド
ラディカルエドワード
Yeah, I know Ed.
Radical Edward.
I hear she's a very beautiful yet whimsical hacker.
すごい美人の
気まぐれハッカーらしいね
違う 違う
あのハッカーは子供じゃ
No, no, that hacker is a child.
そりゃ恐ろしい
いたずら好きのガキだそうじゃ
A brat that loves horrible pranks, I hear.
あら あたしが
隣の奥さんから聞いたのは―
Oh, what I heard from the lady next door is that that hacker is gay.
そのハッカーは
オカマらしいって話よ
ハッカーってエドだろ？
やつは宇宙人なんだ
Hacker?  You mean Ed?
He's an alien!
そんなの みんな言ってるもん
That's what everyone says!
（少年）おっさん おっさん
Hey, man!
ああん？
情報料の代わりに
これ買ってくれよ
Can you buy some of this as the price for the info?
なんだ そりゃ？
What is that?
（少年）知らないの？
地球名物 銘菓ぴよこだよ
You don't know?
It's "Piyoko," a well-known specialty of Earth!
The stolen satellites...
（エド）盗まれた衛星さんたち
どこですかー？
Where are you?
Huh?  What's this?
あれ？ 何これ
情報が地球とつながってない
The information isn't connected to Earth.
衛星同士のつながりだけ
It's connected only between satellites.
And nobody hacked into it...
誰もハッキングしてないなんて
Here, nobody, here.
（んぴゅー）ここ 誰も いない
Always, alone.
ずっと １人
（エド）えっ あれ？
A voice... inside... head...
中の頭で声がする
（エド）誰なの？
Who are you?
えっ 何？
Eh?  What?  What did you just say?
今なんて言ったの？
Who, you?  Here, always.
（んぴゅー）誰？ お前
ここ ずっと
（エド）エドワード
地球から来たネットダイバーだよ
Edward.  A 'net diver from Earth.
（んぴゅー）地球？
Earth?
そうだよ　ねえ 君の名前は？
Yup.  Hey, what's your name?
（んぴゅー）
私はＤ１３５人工衛星に搭載された
衛星制御プログラム
I am the satellite control program on the D-135 artificial satellite.
（エド）
何それ？ あだ名とかないの？
What's that?  Don't you have a nickname?
Then Ed will give you one.
じゃあ エドがつけてあげる
うーんっと えーっと そうだ！
I know!
君はコンピューターだから
“んぴゅー”にしよう
Because you're a computer, you can be MPU!
（んぴゅー）えっ？
MPU!  Cool name!
（エド）
んぴゅー かっこいい へへ
Um...
（んぴゅー）あの…
エドはね エドワード･ウォン･
ハウ･ペペル･チブルスキー４世
Ed is Edward Wong Hau Pepelu Tivrusky the fourth.
Ed for short.
略してエドだよ　よろしく
Nice to meet you!
Here.  A souvenir from Earth.
（ジェット）ほい 地球土産だ
食いもんか？ これ
Is this food?
本当 センス疑うわ
It makes me doubt that they have any sense.
Unlike you, I learned some information.
お前と違って
俺はちゃんと情報 稼いできたぜ
ラディカルエドワードっていう
正体不明のハッカーが怪しいってな
They said that an unknown hacker named Radical Edward is the suspicious one.
It doesn't mean anything if he's unknown.
正体不明じゃ意味ないじゃない
（ジェット）多少は分かったさ
I know, more or less.
大丈夫そうだ
It seems okay.
どういうやつよ？
What kinda thing is it?
（ジェット）
身長２メートルの元バスケ選手で
美人な子供でな
2 meters tall.  Ex-basketball player.  Beautiful kid.
その上 オカマの宇宙人だそうだ
And on top of it, a gay alien.
あーん
（エド）
どうして地球に落書きしたの？
Why did you doodle on Earth?
（んぴゅー）昔々
ゲートの事故が起きるよりずっと昔
Long, long ago, long before the Gate accident...
地球は たくさん人が住んでいる
とてもきれいな星だったのだ
Earth was a beautiful planet where many people lived.
And back then on Earth, there were many...
その頃の地球には こんな絵が
たくさん描いてあって―
...pictures like this, and I always looked at them.
私は ずっと
それを眺めていたものだ
その頃を思い出して―
I remembered those times...
せめて絵だけでも
再現しようとしたのだが…
...and I tried to recreate at least the pictures.
へえー ずっと昔の地球に
こんな落書きがあったんだ
I see, doodles like this were on Earth long ago, too...
（んぴゅー）
そうだ　誤差２％で再現した
Yes.  I recreated them with a 2% margin of error.
（エド）んぴゅーは絵が上手だね
ねえ エドにも描かせてよ
MPU is good at drawing.  Can Ed draw something, too?
あれ どうしたの？
Huh?  What's wrong?
（んぴゅー）これは警察が
ジャミングをかけている
This is...
The police are putting out a jamming signal.
（エド）えー おーい！
んぴゅー？ おーい
Hey!  MPU!  He-e-e-y!
（ジェット）
警察もラディカルエドワードに
接触したらしいな
Looks like the cops touched base with Radical Edward as well.
Listen!  I found your bounty!
（エド）
聞いて！ 賞金首 見つけたよ
なんだ？
What the?
（スパイク）あ？
Bebop!
（エド）ビバップ
衛星ジャック 本当の犯人はね
ハッカーなんかじゃないんだよ
The real culprit in the satellite-jacking wasn't a hacker!
いつからインタラクティブ
チャンネルになった？
Since when do we have an interactive channel?
いや 違う
これはリアルタイムハッキングだ
No, that's not it.
This is a real-time hack job.
Who is this kid?
誰なの？ こいつ
I'll send you MPU's data now.
（エド）今から
んぴゅーのデータを送るからね
Wait a minute, what is MPU?
えっ ちょっと待って
“んぴゅー”って何？
A friend of Ed's.
（エド）エドの友達
Hey, do you know Ed?
おい お前 エド 知ってんのか？
Yeah, because Ed is Ed.
うん　だってエドがエドだもん
I don't care about that.  Who did it?
そんなことは どうでもいいわ
誰が犯人なの？
えーとね 教えてもいいけど
その代わり お願いがあるよ
Um...  I could tell you.
But I have a favor to ask in return.
お願い？
A favor?
ああ はいはい
後でお姉さんが聞いてあげるから
Yeah, yeah.  Your big sister will listen to ya later.
Come on, hurry it up.
ほら 早く
（ジェット）
そうか　捨てられた衛星のＡＩが
勝手に落書きしてるってことか
I see.  The A.I.  From the abandoned satellite is doodling of its own will.
（フェイ）何？ 何なの？
What?  What's up?
And on top of that, it was supposedly listed as...
（ジェット）
おまけに表向きは気象衛星って
ことになってたもんで
...a weather satellite, so nobody suspected anything.
ノーマークだったってわけだ
（フェイ）
この衛星が賞金首ってこと？
Then this satellite is our bounty?
んぴゅーとのアクセスコードが
使えなくなっちゃったから―
Since the access code to MPU can't be used anymore...
直接 衛星の所へ行って
...you need to go directly to the satellite.
（ジェット）
で どうするってんだ？
And what do we do?
Break the antennae that it uses to communicate with the other satellites.
（エド）
仲間の衛星と連絡するための
アンテナを壊して
そしたら
衛星にダイレクトに接続して―
Then make a direct connection to the satellite and download MPU.
んぴゅーをダウンロードするんだよ
And when you do, don't use computer support for firing or flying.
そのとき射撃や飛行に―
コンピューターのサポートは
使わないで
What?  All manual?
何っ？ 全部 手動で？
Yup.  If it notices you, all the attack satellites...
（エド）そう　気付かれたら
んぴゅーとつながってる
攻撃用衛星たちが―
...connected to MPU will automatically fire back.
自動的に反撃してくるからね
これって難しい？
Is this hard?
It's not just hard, it's downright impossible.
難しいどころの話じゃない
そんなの無理だ
It's like playing baseball with no bat!
バットも持たずに
野球をやるようなもんだ
おい スパイク
Hey, Spike.
そういうのが好きなんだよ 俺は
That's the kind of stuff I like.
Hey!  Wait, you.  How do you know about us?
（フェイ）ちょっとあんた
何で私たちのこと？
I know everything.
（エド）みーんな知ってるよ
Last week, you let Ajiz, a bounty on Mars worth 1.5 million, get away...
先週は火星で150万の賞金首
アジツを逃したし―
And in Pyortle before that, the police got to them first...
その前のビョートルのときは
警察に先を越されたし
Are you really that hacker Radical Edward!?
あんた 本当にハッカーの
ラディカルエドワードなの？
Yeah.  You've heard?
そうだよ　知ってるの？
Connect D-7 to #2.  That way, the main cannon will fire without a computer.
（ジェット）Ｄ７を２番と直結だ
それで主砲が
コンピューター抜きで撃てる
I'm trusting you, man...
（スパイク）頼むぜ おい
Now listen.  Avoid using the missile if you can help it.  It's expensive.
（ジェット）いいか？
なるべくミサイルは使うな
高いんだからな
Roger.
（スパイク）了解
1200 to target.
（ジェット）目標まで1200
そろそろ
コンピューター制御をカットだ
It's almost time to cut off computer controls.
Now, the only chance...
いいか？ チャンスは…
一度で十分
Once is enough.
（フェイ）
ところでハッカーじゃなくて
Anyway, you can prove that the satellite itself...
衛星自身が賞金首だってこと
ちゃんと証明できるんでしょうね？
...and not a hacker, is the bounty, right?
Ed can do that.
エド ちゃんとできるよ
Anyway, please, listen to my favor.
それより お願い聞いてくれる約束
そしたら賞金も全部あげるよ
Then I'll give you all the bounty, too.
Oh, you're a surprisingly good kid!
ああら！ 案外いい子じゃん もう
That's it?
あれか
（んぴゅー）誰かが
Someone...
どうだ？
How was it?
Did you get it?
やった？
No, I missed!
（スパイク）いや 外した
手前の衛星が盾になりやがった
The satellite in front of it shielded the blast!
後は全部の衛星を
打ち落とすしかない
Then you have to shoot down all the satellites!
ALL of them!?
これ全部？
（ジェット）
やらねえと こっちがやられる！
If you don't, they'll shoot US down!
ECM, eh?
ＥＣＭか
安物は駄目か
Cheap ones are no good after all...
（スパイク）うおっ
This is getting pointless.
これじゃ きりがねえ　うん？
んぴゅーの20メートル以内に
接近して
Approach to within 20 meters of MPU!
そしたら他の衛星は攻撃できないよ
That way, the other satellites can't attack!
However...
しかし…
Until then, Faye will act as a decoy!
（エド）
その間 フェイがおとりになるよ
ME!?
ああ 私？
よろしく！
Yeah, thanks!
ちょっと！ 早くしてよ
Come on, hurry up!
All right, it's all yours!
よし 頼む！
MPU!
んぴゅー！
MPU?  MPU!?
んぴゅー んぴゅー
Oh, Ed!
（んぴゅー）おお エド
エドか　また会えた
Ed, we meet again.
They have a bounty on you, MPU.
（エド）んぴゅーは
賞金を懸けられてるんだよ
Bounty?
（んぴゅー）賞金？
そう　でも んぴゅーをコピーして
それを捕まえさせれば大丈夫だよ
Yup, but if we copy you and let them catch that, you'll be all right.
All right?
（んぴゅー）大丈夫？
And you must be lonely there alone, MPU.
（エド）それに んぴゅーも
１人じゃ寂しいでしょ？
こっちに来れば
仲間もたくさんいるよ
If you come over here, there are lots of friends.
（んぴゅー）仲間？
Friends?
Here.  It's not scary.
（エド）ほら 怖くないよ
And so, the strange end to this case.
（アナウンサー３）
というわけで
意外な結末を迎えた この事件
The captured criminal was the A.I.  Program for...
捕らえられた犯人は―
地球崩壊以前
打ち上げられたスパイ衛星の―
...a spy satellite that was launched before the Earth was ruined.
人工知能プログラムだったのです
According to government sources from back then, it supposedly would...
当時の政府の資料によりますと
地球からの指示がなくとも―
...continue activity on its own even without commands from Earth.
独自の判断で
行動を続けるとありました
Well, it was the perfect excuse for the cops to go on a hacker hunt.
（ジェット）
ま 警察にしてみりゃ―
ハッカー狩りの
格好の口実だったってわけだな
But anyway, why did it start doodling on the Earth with a laser all of a sudden?
それにしても―
何だって突然 レーザーで地球に
落書きなんてこと始めたんだ？
I'm sure...
そりゃあ―
きっと寂しかったんだろ
...that was because it got lonely.
Yoohoo!  Bebop!
（エド）やっほー！ ビバップ
おーい ここだよ 早くー！
Hey, over here!  Hurry!
Promise, promise!
約束 約束
Well, let's get going now!
（フェイ）
ささ 早く出発しましょう
But the kid is saying something about a promise...
でもこいつ 約束がどうとか…
Promises are made to be broken.
約束なんてのは
破るためにあんのよ
Anyway, let's get going!  Lift off!
いいから 早く出発！ 発進よ
来ない 来ない　あれれー
Not coming, not coming.
きいいいいいいいいいいいいいん
ぶううううううううううううううん
どおおおおおおおおおおおおん
What is this?  What's going on!?
（フェイ）
何よ？ これ どうなってんの？
What did you promise?
（スパイク）
お前 何 約束したんだ？
へへ 約束だよ
It's a promise... to be a member of the Bebop.
ビバップ号の
仲間にしてくれるってね
（パンチ）アミーゴ！
賞金稼ぎの諸君
Amigo!  All you bounty hunters!
It's finally time for BIG SHOT!
（ジュディ）お待ちかね
ビッグショットの時間よ
Now, today's hot news.
（パンチ）
さて 本日のホットニュース！
捕まった衛星落書き犯のことは
聞いたよね？
You've heard about the doodling satellite that got caught, right?
もちろん！
すごい賞金 懸かってたわよね
Of course!  It had a big bounty on it!
ついさっき 地球の警察から
発表があったんだけど
Just a few moments ago, the Earth police made an official report.
なに なに？
What was it?
この賞金は人間および生命体のみを
対象とするものであり―
"This bounty is only for when humans or other life forms are the targets."
コンピュータープログラムに
おいては―
"It is difficult to determine whether or not a computer program is a life form."
それを生命体と確定することが
困難である
そもそも
生命倫理的見地からして…
"To begin with, from the viewpoint of biological logistics..."
なあに？ それ　よく分かんない
What's that?  I don't understand well.
ま 要するに
無生物には金は払えんってことだ
In other words, they can't pay up on nonliving things!
あーら 捕まえた人 ご愁傷さま
Oh, my!
To those who caught it, I feel sorry for you!
（スパイク）なあ ジェット
Hey, Jet, did you know that there are three things that I hate?
俺の嫌いなもんが三つあるって
知ってたか？
（ジェット）さあな
Whatever...
（スパイク）
ガキと けだもんと―
Rugrats...
...beasts...
...and tomboys.
はねっ返りの女だ
ほーお
Don't give me that!
（スパイク）“ほー”じゃねえよ
どうして その三つが
そろいもそろってここにいるんだよ
Why do we have all three neatly gathered here!?
（エド）エド ぴよこ大好き
Ed loves Piyokos!
（ジェット）
また賞金が入らねえっていうのに…
And once again we didn't get any bounty...
（フェイ）あら あんた
女の子なの？
Hey, wait, you're a girl?
（エド）いひひひ
Really, nothing good comes outta Earth!
（ジェット）全く
地球産には ろくなもんはねえ
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（フェイ）
逃げた女にゃ未練はないが―
No regrets about the woman who ran away...
心に刺さる小さなとげ
...but a small thorn still pricks the heart.
Letting one flow along with time itself...
時の流れに身を任せ
一人 生きては きたけれど―
...living all alone from that day to this.
寄せては返す波の音(ね)に
心引かれる渡り鳥
But to the sounds of waves that come and go...
...the migrating birds find their hearts drawn.
次回「ガニメデ慕情」
Next episode: Ganymede Elegy.
ジェット･ブラック
心を込めて歌い上げます
Jet Black will sing it up full of soul.